Sachin Mandhotra

Python developer/Data Scientist/ML Enthusiast

I'm an experienced professional (1.7 years) with work history in domains including development in python,ETL tools and Data science field. I would describe myself as a person who has the drive, confidence and resilience to work. I try to be creative and innovative and reflect the same in my work. I am open to challenges and currently seeking a Data Scientist/Machine Learning Engineer position with an Organization to achieve long-term goals and growth opportunities.



- O Chandigarh, India
- github.com/sachinm02

- 7018308287/8352036639
- in linkedin.com/in/sachin-mandhotra-24597512b

WORK EXPERIENCE

Python Developer

1 Touch Development(StartUp)

02/2020 - 04/2020

Chandigarh,India

Business Analyst/Python DeveloperGrazitti Interactive

10/2018 - 01/2020

Panchkula,India

PROJECTS

Web Scraping - Python, Beautiful Soup & Selenium (04/2020 - 04/2020)

 Created Python script for scraping images and text data from fashion website and then storing them in structured format.

Customer Case Stage Prediction (10/2019 - 11/2019)

 Worked on creating a classification model using NLP to predict the stage of customer case posted on Agent Support Channels.

Park Attendance Prediction Model (08/2019 - 10/2019)

- Used Alteryx to create workflows for fetching weather data from vertica, combining it with each parks daily and hourly attendance along with other data preprocessing steps.
- Used Regression model for predicting daily and hourly attendance in each park to minimize labor costs and increase Revenue.

Data-warehousing for Marketo (08/2019 - 08/2019)

- Developed Python script for automating the process of fetching Leads data.
- Pushing the fetched data to SQL server table using Python script.

UJET - Data Warehousing (02/2019 - 03/2019)

 Fetching and Parsing of data from ujet api endpoint and Dumping of data incrementally into AWS Redshift Database using Python.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's of Technology

Jawahar Lal Nehru Govt. Engineering College

08/2014 - 05/2018

Mandi ,Himachal Pradesh

Courses

- Electronics and Communication Engineering (ECE) secured 69 % in B.Tech.
- SECONDARY EDUCATION -> (CBSE)
- 10th 9.8 CGPA (Science)
- 12th 87.60 % (Non-Medical)

SKILLS



SELF LEARNINGS

Completed course on NLP from Udemy (11/2020 - 12/2020)

StudiedNLTK/Spacy for various NLP related tasks.

Completed course on Selenium and Neo4j from Udemy (03/2020 - 04/2020)

Studied about Web scraping and Graph Database concepts

Machine Learning A-Z with Python (UDEMY) (01/2019 - 02/2019)

Studied Machine Learning Course With Python

CERTIFICATES

Alteryx Core Certified (12/2018 - Present)

Cleared Alteryx Core Certification Exam organised by Alteryx

Industrial Training (Python) (06/2017 - 07/2017)

Acquired knowledge of HTML5, MySQL, Python(Basics)

LANGUAGES

INTERESTS

Machine Learning NLP Business Analytics

Playing Video Games Cricket Football

Trekking Watching TV shows